Now that you understand the importance of developing in a clean and modular way,
既然你已经理解了 以整洁和模块化方式开发的重要性
let's break down what this means in code.
让我们看看在代码中具体应该怎么做
The first tip for writing clean code,
编写整洁代码的第一个提示
is to use meaningful descriptive names for your variables and functions.
是为变量和函数使用有意义的描述性名称
This can help you explain most of your code without comments.
这可以帮助你解释大部分代码而无需注释
Take a look at this code that initializes a list of student test scores, prints the mean,
看看这段代码 其中初始化了一个学生考试成绩列表 打印均值
curves each score by multiplying its square root by 10,
通过将每个分数的平方根乘以 10 得出转换后的分数
and then prints the mean of the new curved scores.
然后打印转换后的分数均值
With this code, you wouldn't know what was happening right away without these comments.
这段代码如果没有注释 你无法立即明白代码的作用
See how this compares to this cleaner code,
看看与这段更整洁代码的对比
which conveys the same purpose without the comments.
没有注释就表达了同样的目的
Now, we know what both of these lists stand for without the comments,
现在 没有注释的情况下 我们知道这两个列表代表了什么
which will help us throughout the program wherever these variables are used.
对这些变量在整个程序中的使用都很有帮助
We also use the function with a descriptive name,
我们还使用了具有描述性名称的函数 mean
mean, instead of running a calculation each time.
而不是每次都进行计算
This not only helps readability,
这不仅有助于提高可读性
but follows the DRY principle or don't repeat
也遵循了 DRY 原则 即不要重复自己 (Don't Repeat Yourself)
yourself that is important to writing modular code,
这个原则对编写模块化代码很重要
which we'll talk more about later.
我们稍后会深入讲解
In addition, we imported the math module to use
另外 我们导入了 math 模块来使用
its square root method instead of raising each score to 0.5 with double asterisks,
它的 sqrt 方法 而不是用双星号 0.5 来计算
which isn't only more readable,
这不仅更具可读性
but also faster in Python 3.
在 Python 3 中的运行速度也更快
Try testing how effective your names are by asking a fellow programmer to guess
尝试让其他程序员同事在不查看代码的情况下
the purpose of a function or variable based on its name without looking at your code.
通过名称猜测函数或变量的目的 可以验证你的名称有效性
Coming up with meaningful names often requires effort to get right.
通常需要一些努力才能想出有意义的名称
Here are some guidelines.
以下是一些指导原则
Let's start with the first guideline.
第一个原则
Be descriptive, and when appropriate,
具有描述性 并且在恰当的时候
try implying the type of whatever you're naming.
尝试暗示你所命名的类型
Notice we call this list,
请注意我们称这个列表为
age list instead of ages,
age_list 而不是 ages
which helps us avoid confusing the integer age and the list of ages later in this code.
这有助于避免混淆 int 型的 age 变量和后续代码中的 age 列表
For Booleans, it's often helpful to prefix the name with words
对于布尔值来说 为名称添加 is 或 has 前缀通常
like is or as to make it clear that it's a condition.
可以表明这是一个条件
You can also use parts of speech to imply types by
你还可以使用词性来表示类型
using verbs for functions and nouns for variables.
对函数名使用动词 对变量名使用名词
Normally, you don't want to use abbreviations unless the word will be used many,
通常情况下 你不应该使用缩写 除非该单词将被使用很多很多次
many times, and you especially don't want single letter names.
尤其不应该使用单个字母的名称
However, exceptions include names for counters such as i in this example,
但是 计数器的名称是例外情况 例如本例中的 i
as well as common variable names using math like,
数学中常见的变量名称也是例外
x, y, t, and so on.
比如 x y t 等等
Choosing when these exceptions can be made
选择何时适用于这些例外情况
can be determined based on your audience for the code.
根据你的代码受众而决定
If you work with other data scientists,
如果你与其他数据科学家合作
certain variables may be common knowledge.
某些特定的变量名可能是常识
While if you work with full-stack engineers,
如果你和全栈工程师一起工作
it might be necessary to provide more descriptive names in these cases as well.
在这些情况下可能还需要提供更具描述性的名称
However, long names do not always mean meaningful names.
但是 长名称并不总是意味着有意义的名称
You should be descriptive,
你应该使用描述性的名称
but not with more characters than necessary.
但没有超过必要的字符
This first example is very verbose.
这里的第一个例子非常啰嗦
This function computes the number of
此函数计算的是
unique values in a list regardless of what that list is.
列表中的唯一值的数量 无论列表是什么
So, we can generalize and remove of names list from the function name,
所以 我们可以从函数名中删除 of_name_list
and replace the argument name with arr,
并用 arr 替换参数名称
which is standard to represent an arbitrary array.
这是表示任意数组 (array) 的标准名称
In addition, implementation details are unnecessary to include in a function name.
此外 实现的细节不必包含在函数名中
So, we can remove with set from the function name as well.
因此 我们也可以从函数名中删除 with_set
The resulting function is much more clean and concise while still being descriptive.
由此产生的函数名更加整洁精炼 同时仍然具有描述性
Another tip for writing clean code is to use whitespace properly.
编写整洁代码的另一个提示是正确使用空白
Code with poor or inconsistent spacing is the worst.
没有空白或者空白不一致的代码是最差的
Take a look at this mess.
看看这段混乱的代码
If you were handed this code as a developer,
如果你作为开发人员处理这样的代码
the first thing you should do is fix the whitespace and make it consistent.
需要做的第一件事就是修复空白并使其保持一致性
This is much nicer to read and work with.
这样使代码更易阅读和使用
Organize your code with consistent indentation.
使用一致的缩进来组织代码
The standard for Python is using four spaces for each indent,
Python 的标准是每个缩进使用四个空格
unlike we have here.
而不是像这里的一样
Also, be sure to separate sections with
另外 请务必将每个代码块用空行分开
blank lines to make it easier to organize and read.
使其更容易组织和阅读
Lastly, try to limit your lines to around 79 characters.
最后 尝试将每行限制为大约 79 个字符
Seventy-nine is the guideline given in the PEP 8 Style Guide.
79 是 PEP 8 风格指南中给出的规范
In many good text editors,
在很多优秀的文本编辑器中
there's a setting to display a subtle line
有设置可以显示一个浅色的竖线
that indicates where the 79 character limit is.
表示 79 个字符限制的位置
Notice how much clear it is to read
注意到这样阅读起来有多么清晰了吗？
this Mongo query in this code with shorter lines and proper indentation.
这段代码中用较短的行和适当的缩进显示 Mongo 查询
Also, notice how much cleaner this ending part of the code is where we call create plot.
另外 注意一下代码的结尾部分 调用 plot 函数比之前整洁的多
For more guidelines on this,
有关此问题的更多指导规范
check out the code layout section of PEP 8 in the notes below.
请查看下面讲师注释中的链接 关于 PEP 8 的代码布局部分